creating your own GitHub Docker
container
action right everybody's doing this
right now and there are lots of
different ways to do this and get the
input and there are a lot of unsafe ways
to do this uh ways that you can really
shoot yourself in the foot um not to
mention making your life a lot more
problematic um and I I'm still new to
this so as I begin thank you for that
um everybody's saying hi here are some
things that I've discovered initially
about GitHub actions and how they're
deployed and how they're implemented
that I want people to consider and right
off the bat I'm going to show you a
deployment that ran where I ultimately
decided to pass environment variables
into the entry point of the container
this specifically fori there's many ways
you can do dock
containers uh I mean GitHub containers
but Docker containers are by far the
best and you can use your own Runner and
everything but but I what I want bring
attention to here is you see here I'm
using the wi keyword to pass input uh
which we'll get into how to define that
in a second and you can see that it
follows the convention here by passing
you know mounting I guess these
environment variables using Docker run
and it call it puts input underscore and
it uppercases all of it and everything
but that's not all it does it also
passes according to the specification it
also um must require that you put an
argument line down here but if you keep
going farther on you start to see that
it when the
implementation um you see that it passes
it as an argument to the beginning and
this is extremely confusing if you're
just coming at this if if when you see
the term args as a Unix person
um you immediately assume it's going to
be you know an argument and another
argument and another argument passed to
the command line and I mean by looking
at this example again you can imagine
that I would have in my case if I had
passed it with wi I would have had like
five or six or seven of them right and
then immediately the follow-up question
to this is well how do I even get to the
data right and and so let's go back to
the other thing um this is this is how
you know you would so this is which one
are you going to use so if you're a Unix
person you at this point you're at least
a little bit confused right because
you're like okay how shall I use this
data how shall I process this in my
entrypoint uh file by the way don't call
it entrypoint.sh that just shows how
little the people understood Unix who
created actions um you should never put
a suffix on a on a script like that ever
um and there's another rant about that
but anyway so this input so you're like
which one is it right and am I going to
use this environment variable in my
script or am I going to use uh the first
positional parameter in my script which
one is it the answer is both it uses
both of them and why the hell would you
ever want to do that I don't understand
this at all and you don't need to
understand it because let me show you
further if you read on further down into
the documentation here you'll see that
they actually warn you against doing it
they warn you against doing it and they
say if you use the args line it's down
here below someplace I got to find it
again if you use the args put with here
right that's how it gets used um but if
you use the args line it actually uses
the CMD format of the of of the um ex
entry point executable um and which is
completely insecure in fact they
encourage you to use a shell - c which I
don't have in front of me right now but
you don't really need to know about any
of that just don't do it I'm serious
don't do it do do environment variables
the takeaway from this is very obvious
and simple use environment variables
right if you if you do this instead of
using in fact I personally unless
somebody can strongly convince me
otherwise I am never using the with
keyword in any custom action that I ever
make and the reason is I believe it
encourages people to do things that are
really grossly insecure uh because of
the way entry points are are set up in
Darker containers uh GitHub actions
which is a a really deep dive um that
maybe we'll go to in another video um uh
but yeah so if they're meant to be
sourced I agree so so the the safer
thing to do here is and and the more
obvious thing to do and the simpler
thing is to just use the EnV uh tag when
you're creating your custom actions
because this way you know exactly what
they are you name them what you want
them to be named and you end up with
scripts that get mounted look see it
mounts them it mounts them using your
your environment variables and your
entry points become much simpler because
at that point you don't have to be as
crazy uh and you can make an entry point
that this is a sample the entry point
but instead of I I use the other one
right but instead of using hello dollar
one you use dollar user and you end up
with a shell script that's very reusable
in fact there's no reason that I could
not use this shell script and run it you
know and test it without it being used
in the context of GitHub actions which
is kind of one of those things you want
to consider do I even really need this
to be a a GI of action right so if
you're going to use a Docker container
which is probably a good idea then you
can write your entry point and your you
know your Docker file can can be uh
super simple as mine is your Docker file
can just be super simple and it can call
an entry point and if you decide you
need to put other things in there for
example in my case I'll probably be
adding uh
SSH um and I don't know what maybe tar
if it's not already there in the Aline
one I don't know but if you needed to
add stuff in there you could the point
is is this nice happy entry point file
um is now can be used anywhere right and
it you it's very easier it's much easier
to read because you've got you've got
you know actual environment variables in
here that are just being called now if
you want to create your own prefix for
that fine but as we saw these these
environment variables are automatically
passed using their exact names if you
use the EnV directive in your custom
actions so the takeaway is very simple
use environment variables period if you
use environment variables which is
already a thing and and I'm not going to
go down the rabbit hole of whether using
environment variables is secure in the
containerized world it's been adopted as
the standard for over 10 years at this
point passing data through environment
variables is the standard way to do it
including secrets and if you just use
environment variables then you are not
exposed to the security problems that
are inherent when you use their wi
syntax and all the crap that they do by
passing positional parameters to the
entry point script you don't even have
to read the section that talks about
using shell DC in order to get variable
expansion because it's no longer
relevant you can just say goodbye
insecure stupid practice and use
environment variables as God intended
when used with containers if you're not
doing this make sure you know what
you're doing because I guarantee you
that there are are a lot of
vulnerabilities out there right now that
are doing entry points incorrectly and
are subject to to uh shell injection
attacks and I may look forward to
finding some of those avoid avoid being
hacked just use environment variables